Summary

I'm a professional Web Developer who has been in the business since 1999. During my career, I've worked for many interactive agencies on brands such as Microsoft, Xbox, Ford, Land Rover, The Financial Times, BT, Cohn & Wolfe.

I have a good eye for detail and an interest in building high quality user interfaces. I have a wide range of skills that cover both front and backend development. I like to learn and experiment with new technologies, and I have good analytical and problem solving skills.

The whole development process interests me. I am always keen to learn more and improve my skills. I'm familiar with Agile and have worked in large teams in a Test Driven, Continuous Integration environment.

Skills

- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, LESS
- JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS
- Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP
- WordPress, Drupal, AEM/CQ5, OpenCart
- Git, Subversion, JIRA
- Vagrant, VirtualBox

- Grunt, Gulp, Bower
- Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator
- Agile, Continuous Integration
- SEO, SMO, Analytics
- Responsive Web Design
- Web Standards, Accessibility

Experience

Owner / Web Developer

ID1 Media, May 2006 - Present

I've been working as a freelance web developer for a number of years. During this time I've worked on projects large and small for a wide range of clients. This has allowed me to develop a range of skills spanning the industry.

Senior Web Developer

VCCP, October 2015 (2 weeks) www.chimegroup.com

Brought in to complete an ongoing project in time for launch. Worked to tight deadlines to ensure templates matched responsive designs and worked across browsers and mobile devices.

- HTML5, CSS3, LESS, JavaScript, jQuery, WordPress
- Gulp, Git, JIRA, Photoshop

Interactive Web Developer

VML London, February 2015 – May 2015 (4 months, 1 extension) www.virginactive.co.uk

Worked on two projects. The first, in a small team building a responsive, single page app. It featured navigational map and timeline components built with Google Maps and D3 respectively. The second, working in a large Agile team on a responsive website redesign and rebuild.

- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript, AngularJS, Google Maps, D3
- Gulp, Git, IIRA, Photoshop, Illustrator

Web Developer

Pixelgroup, November 2014 - December 2014 (5 weeks)

Developed the main interface of an online gaming app; a fluid width / height design built using the AngularJS framework and Velocity animation library.

- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript, AngularJS, Velocity
- Grunt, Bower, Git, Photoshop, Illustrator

Interactive Web Developer

VML London, March 2014 - October 2014 (8 months, 1 extension)

Worked as part of a large team in a test driven, Agile environment. Developed user interfaces for CMS websites built on the AEM/CQ5 platform. Maintained a CSS style guide to demonstrate and document UI components.

- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript, AngularJS, AEM/CQ5
- · Vagrant, Subversion, JIRA, Photoshop, Illustrator

Interactive Web Developer

VML London, November 2013 - January 2014 (2 months, 1 extension)

Developed a responsive, content aggregation site for an online campaign. Used the Isotope library for the main view layout. Built to be cross-browser compatible on both desktop and mobile devices.

- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript, jQuery, RequireJS, Isotope
- Subversion, JIRA, Photoshop

Web Developer

Critical Mass, April 2013 - July 2013 (4 months, 2 extensions)

Worked as a senior member of a team building a large multi-lingual website. Developed the front-end templates for an e-commerce site, ready for integration into a Java Spring framework.

- HTML5, CSS3, LESS, JavaScript, jQuery
- Git, JIRA, Photoshop

Other Positions

Project Manager / Web Developer *Digital Vision, January 2002 - February 2005*

Lead Developer *AQKA, July 1999 - June 2001*

Education

Humberside University, Hull

BSc Mechanical Engineering and Manufacturing Systems, 1995 – 1999

Languages

Spanish (limited working proficiency).

Interests

Kitesurfing, foreign languages, football.